Guide to the Daniel C. Roper Papers, 1860-1958 RL.01106
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Alphabetical, 1927-1943, undated (bulk 1933-1938)
  - Watson, E. O., 1928-1932 (Box 25)
  - Webb, George T., 1932 (Box 25)
  - Wesley, Lofton S., 1928 (Box 25)
  - Wetherill, Samuel P., 1939 (Box 25)
  - Wg-Wl, 1928-1940 (Box 25)
  - White House, miscellaneous memoranda, 1933-1936 (Box 25)
  - Wiggins, A. Lee M., 1930-1940 (Box 25)
  - William, Maurice, 1931-1939 (Box 25)
  - Williams, Dixon C., 1927-1930 (Box 25)
  - Williams, J. Lester, 1930-1939 (Box 25)
  - Williams, Wayne C., 1928-1939 (Box 25)
  - Wilson, Frank R., 1939 (Box 25)
  - Wilson, Luke I., 1928-1932 (Box 25)
  - Wilson, William B. 1928-1931 (Box 25)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1916-1924 (Box 25)
  - Winton, David J., 1932 (Box 25)
  - Wm-Wz, 1930-1939 (Box 25)
  - Woodson, Urey, 1930-1939 (Box 25)
  - Woolley, Robert M., 1932-1939 (Box 25)
  - Wyvell, Manton M., 1928-1932 (Box 25)
  - Y, 1928-1939 (Box 25)
  - Yellowley, Edward C., 1932-1939 (Box 25)
  - Younger, Donald, 1928-1933 (Box 25)
  - Z, 1932-1939 (Box 25)
  - Zapf, Lacey C., 1932-1939 (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1936-1943 (Box 25)
  - Volumes: (Box 26)
    - (Congratulations upon Roper's appointment as Secretary of Commerce) (Box 26)
    - Letterbook, 1933 (Box 26)
    - Special letters of congratulation to Daniel C. Roper, March 4, 1933 (Box 26)
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1913-1943, undated (bulk 1933-1938)
  Chiefly typed transcripts, in bound and loose form, of Roper's public addresses and statements. The majority, many of which were broadcast over national radio, were delivered while Roper was Commissioner of Internal Revenue or Secretary of Commerce. Also includes two typed, unbound book manuscripts containing proofreaders' marks; correspondence about speaking engagements and book publication; and a small amount of press releases, printed speeches, speeches by others, and background material for speeches and books. Volumes contain some duplicates of loose material in the series.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Addresses, 1913-1940, undated, 16 folders (Box 27)
  - Addresses: List of Speeches Given by Roper, 1933-1938 (Box 27)
  - Addresses, 1933-1936(4 vols.) (Box 28)
  - Addresses, 1937-1938(2 vols.) (Box 29)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1938 (Box 29)
  - Corespondence and statements, 1938 (Box 29)
  - Fifty Years of Public Life:
    - Correspondence, 1919-1943 (Box 29)
    - Manuscript, 1941, 4 folders (Box 29)
    - Notes, 1921-1941 (Box 29)
    - Notes, undated (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous, 1941, undated (Box 30)
  - A Political History of the United States:
    - Manuscript, undated, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous, 1934, undated (Box 30)
  - Quotations and References, 1936-1937, undated (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous, 1938, undated (Box 30)
- Financial Papers Series, 1884-1943, undated, bulk 1921-1940
  Contains records of the personal finances of Roper, his wife, and children, including investments in a number of businesses and real estate holdings, primarily in the form of correspondence with bankers, stock brokers and tenants. Also contains balance sheets; tax returns; records of stock transfer; lists of assets; profit and loss statements; financial statements from banks, brokerage houses, and various companies; receipts for dividends and taxes; and a few mortgage and lease agreements. Roper held major accounts with the City Bank Farmers' Trust Company (previously Farmers' Loan and Trust Company). Includes a number of financial record books documenting the above investments. A scrapbook generated by Roper's employment at the Marlin Rockwell Corporation contains correspondence, legal agreements, financial records, clippings, reports, and receipts.
  Two subseries: Loose papers and Volumes, each arranged chronologically. Loose items removed from volumes and scrapbook have been placed in adjacent folders.
  - Loose Papers
    - 1884-1943, n.d:Receipts, Miscellaneous (Box 30)
    - 1921-1937:Tax Returns (Box 30)
    - 1926-1928:Farms, N.C. and S.C. (Box 30)
    - 1926-1938: Miami, Fla., property (Box 30)
    - 1926-1929:Miscellaneous (Box 30)
    - 1927-1928: Roper, Hagerman, Hurrey, and Parks (Box 30)
    - 1927-1932:Roper children (Box 30)
    - 1928:Investments (Box 30)
    - 1928-1937: Bradenton, Fla., property (Box 30)
    - 1929: City Bank Farmers' Trust Co., custodian account
      - Income Tax (Box 30)
      - Investments (Box 30)
    - 1929-1930:Farms, N.C. and S.C. (Box 30)
    - 1930: Roper, Hagerman, Hurrey, and Dudley (Box 30)
    - 1930-1931: City Bank Farmers' Trust Co., custodian account (Box 30)
    - 1930-1932:Investments, 2 folders (Box 30)
    - 1930-1939: City Bank Farmers' Trust Co., trust agreements (Box 31)
    - 1931:Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    - 1931-1932:Farms, N.C. and S.C. (Box 31)
    - 1932:Brokerage statements, 2 folders
      - Dividend Memoranda (Box 31)
    - 1932-1933: City Bank Farmers' Trust Co. (Box 31)
    - 1932-1934: Roper, Hurrey, and Dudley (Box 31)
    - 1932-1935:Taxes, South Carolina property
      - Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    - 1933:Farms, N. C. and S.C. (Box 31)
    - 1934: City Bank Farmers' Trust Co. custodian account (Box 31)
    - 1934-1936:Farms, N.C. and S.C. (Box 31)
    - 1935-1936: City Bank Farmers' Trust Co., custodian account (Box 31)
    - 1936-1940:Income Tax (Box 31)
    - 1936-1937:Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    - 1937: City Bank Farmers' Trust Co., custodian account (Box 31)
    - 1937-1938:Farms, N.C. and S.C.
      - Investments (Box 31)
      - Johnston, Lemon, and Co. (Box 31)
    - 1937-1940:Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    - 1938: New Orleans, La., property (Box 31)
    - 1938-1940, undated: City Bank Farmers' Trust Co., custodian account (Box 31)
  - Volumes
    - Financial Record Books: 1921-1929, 1939(2 vols.) (Box 31)
    - Financial Record Books: 1928-1937(8 vols.) (Box 32)
    - Scrapbook: 1918-1921: (Box 32)
- Clippings Series, 1860-1944, undated (bulk 1910-1940)
  Chiefly loose clippings and clippings in scrapbooks, documenting Roper's political career and contemporary events. Scrapbooks also contain some correspondence, speeches, charts, printed materials and photographs.
  Loose clippings are arranged chronologically, followed by two subject folders of clippings, and then the scrapbooks. The scrapbooks are arranged chronologically, with loose items contained in adjacent files.
  - 1919-1944, undated, 4 folders (Box 32)
  - Air Mail Service, 1933-1934, undated (Box 33)
  - Political, 1933-1934, undated (Box 33)
  - Scrapbooks:
    - 1860-1908 (Box 33)
    - 1903-1920 (Box 33)
    - 1913-1917, undated (Box 33)
    - 1923-1926 (Box 33)
    - 1930-1931 (Box 34)
    - 1932 (Box 34)
    - 1933 (Box 34)
    - 1934-1935: (Box 34)
    - 1936, Jan.-June: (Box 34)
    - 1936, July-1938(no.1), (3 vols.) (Box 35)
    - 1938(no. 2) (Box 35)
  - King George VI and Queen Elizabeth Visit to Canada, 1939 (loose items), 2 folders (Box 36)
  - Scrapbook: My Clippings of Their Majesties' Visit to Canada, 1939 (Box 36)
- Miscellaneous Series, 1884-1958, undated (bulk 1920-1940)
  Chiefly loose photographs of Roper, his family, and professional associates, including prominent politicians. Most of the latter were taken during the time of his cabinet post, and many have captions attached. Also includes invitations, legal papers, printed material, programs to banquets and other events, correspondence regarding photographs, and five volumes.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material. Photographs are arranged alphabetically by name of subject in a Pictures subseries at the end, which includes one photograph album.
  - Invitations, 1923-1943, undated, 4 folders (Box 37)
  - Legal Papers, 1904, 1929 (Box 37)
  - Printed Material, 1913-1943 (Box 37)
  - Programs, 1934-1958, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Volume: Commonplace Book, 1906-1912 (Box 37)
  - Volume: The Guilds of America, 1933 (Box 37)
  - Volumes, 1928, undated (Box 37)
  - Pictures:
    - Correspondence, 1936-1938, undated (Box 37)
    - Baruch, Bernard M., 1920 (Box 37)
    - British Royal Family, 1938-1939 (Box 37)
    - Bryan, William Jennings, undated (Box 37)
    - Byrnes, James F., 1941 (Box 37)
    - Cleveland, Grover, 1908, undated (Box 37)
    - Daniels, Josephus, 1937-1947 (Box 37)
    - Dodd, William E., undated (Box 37)
    - Duke University, undated (Box 37)
    - Harriman, W. Averell, undated (Box 37)
    - House, Edward M., 1924 (Box 37)
    - Ickes, Harold, undated (Box 37)
    - Luther, Hans, 1937 (Box 37)
    - Pan-American Union, 1933-1937 (Box 37)
    - Rainey, Henry T., 1934 (Box 37)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, undated (Box 37)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1934-1937, undated (Box 37)
    - Roosevelt, Sarah, 1940 (Box 37)
    - Roper, Daniel C., 1884-1938, undated, 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Roper Family, 1907-1948, undated, 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Taft, William H., 1924 (Box 37)
    - United States Supreme Court, undated (Box 37)
    - Washington, D.C., undated (Box 37)
    - Wilson, Woodrow, undated (Box 37)
    - People, A-Z and Miscellaneous, 1934-1939, undated (Box 37)
    - Photograph Album, Sugar Story in Pictures, undated (Box 37)
- Oversize Materials
  - Alphabetical Series
    - A-Z, 1892-1938, undated, 2 folders (Box 38)
    - A-Z, 1928-1938, undated (Oversize-folder Folder 1)
  - Writings and Speeches Series
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Oversize-folder Folder 1)
  - Clippings Series
    - Scrapbook, 1860-1908 (Insert), undated (Box 38)
  - Financial Papers Series
    - 1926-1928:Farms, N.C. and S.C. (Box 38)
    - 1926-1936: Miami, Fla. property (Box 38)
    - 1927-1928: Roper, Hagerman, Hurrey and Parks (Box 38)
    - 1927-1931:Roper children (Box 38)
    - 1929:Investments (Box 38)
    - 1932:Brokerage statements, Daniel C. Roper (Box 38)
    - 1932:Brokerage statements, Lou McKenzie Roper (Box 38)
    - 1935: Daniel C. Roper (Box 38)
    - 1921-1937:Tax Returns (Box 39)
    - 1926-1940:Miscellaneous (Box 39)
    - 1931-1939: City Bank Farmers' Trust Company: custodian account (Box 39)
    - Volume: Financial Record Book, 1922-1928 (Box 39)
    - 1926-1936:Miami, Fla. property (Oversize-folder OC:III:3)
    - 1932-1938:Miscellaneous (Oversize-folder OC:III:3)
  - Miscellaneous Series: Pictures
    - 1920-1946, undated, 2 folders (Box 39)
    - 1917-1941, undated, 3 folders (Box 40)